Nemanja Manojlovic Medior Full Stack Engineer & UI/UX Designer

Contact Info

E-mail: contact@nemanjamanojlovic.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nemania-manoilovic/

GitHub: https://github.com/Manojlovic1998

Portfolio Website: https://manojlovic1998.github.io/personal-portfolio/

Summary:

I am a 24-year-old software engineer from Sweden with 2 years of experience in the industry. I am highly versatile and enthusiastic, with a quick learning ability. I have a strong background in full stack development, UI/UX design, and cloud infrastructure. My current focus is on technologies such as React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJS, Typescript, Yarn, NPM, Github, Github Actions, Monorepo automation, Docker, React Native, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL, and more.

Education:

- BSc in Computer Science (2023-ongoing), University of London, Goldsmiths https://www.gold.ac.uk/
- Full Stack Developer (2019-2021) Code Institute, Dublin, Ireland https://codeinstitute.net/global/
- Natural Science (2014-2017) International Baccalaureate, Stockholm, Sweden https://www.ibo.org/

Experience:

- Nebulr Group AB (2022-ongoing):
 - Working on the creation and maintenance of underlying infrastructure for new products.
 - Design and implementation of proprietary cloud microservice solutions, client-side plugins (React, CLI, SDKs), and automation of tasks (DevOps, GitHub Actions, Docker, K8s).
 - Administration and creation of monorepos with project's associated stack toolchains (Webpack, yarn, npm, Babel, Typescript, Tailwind, PostCSS, ESLint).
 - Built microservice that is using Auth 2.0 and OpenID Connect protocol to grant access to user resources.
 - Built PoC integration of Ace, an open-source in-browser IDE for allowing code interoperability.
- Self-Employed, Freelancing (2021-2022):
 - On-demand creation and optimization of websites for other firms.
 - On-demand, UI and UX design development and implementation for firms.

Technical Knowledge:

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, Bash, Ruby, HTML5, CSS, SASS
- Terminal, OS & IDE Preferences: Tmux (multiplexer), Alacritty (Shell Emulator), Z
 Shell, MacOS or Debian-based Linux Distros, Isof (tool for fast traversing system files and directories), VSCode (prefer not limited to), GitPod
- Data Management: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Frameworks, Libraries & Running Environments: React, Redux, Next, Django, Flask, Three.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Webpack, jQuery, GSAP, Docker, Docker-compose, Kubernetes, Kubectl, Skaffold, Minikube, Dokku, NPM, Yarn, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQl, NodeJS
- Cloud (laaS, PaaS, SaaS): GCP, AWS, Heroku, Digital Ocean, Azure
- Design: UX/UI, Logo Design, Vector Design, 3D Design and Modelling, Mockups, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Figma, Blender
- Version Control & Cloud Repo Hosting Services: Git tool, GitHub, Gitlab, gh CLI (GitHub CLI), LazyGit (CLI tool written in Go)

Certificates of Completion:

- Vue The Complete Guide <u>https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-8a31d0cf-a0bc-4d08-af75-1c569a44927a/</u>
- Docker & Kubernetes: The Complete Guide https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-953c2a69-be24-4e42-a711-47fd5c408a43/
- React The Complete Guide (Hooks, React Router, Redux, NextJS)
 https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-4d678ab1-db33-404c-a73c-8ce8cd19e340/
- Google Cloud Essentials:
 https://www.qwiklabs.com/public_profiles/820d282f-3d3c-4b73-804e-3605e0d40de3/badges/1717710?utm_medium=social&utm_source=linkedin&utm_campaign=ql-social-share
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals
 https://www.credly.com/badges/8c936ace-226b-44d1-a9e1-f941aaece951?source=linked-in-profile
- Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals
 https://www.credly.com/badges/5d629944-ce63-45e9-8d07-2dca5d8b1164?source=linked_in_profile
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
 https://www.credly.com/badges/c88ba63d-0676-4dd0-863f-8c564f96cf60?source=link
 ed in profile
- Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Fundamentals
 https://www.credly.com/earner/earned/badge/9bcbdaa0-c25b-4436-8679-4dee1623e
- The Git & GitHub Bootcamp https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-4d678ab1-db33-404c-a73c-8ce8cd19e340/

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals
 https://www.credly.com/badges/2bfb43d9-58ef-487f-ab22-9d9721104137?source=linked in profile

Cultural Volunteer Work

For the International Red Cross in Serbia, I volunteered at a school for children with special needs providing help and guidance in physical exercises, swimming, and other associated activities.

Personal Habits

- Prolific Learner
- Problem-solving
- Adaptability
- Organization
- Willingness to Learn
- Empathy
- Open-mindedness
- Creativity

Hobbies & Interests

- Programming
- Reading
- Photography
- Fitness
- Nutrition
- Dogs
- Design

Languages

- Mother Tongue Serbian
- Second Language English
- Third Language Swedish